Kheel, Theodore W. Non-Profit Organization Files 6021/006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Non-Profit Organization Files
1979-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel, Theodore W.
6021/006
7.11 cubic feet
7.1 linear ft.
Papers.
5767574
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 28, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officialscontacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs 6017: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence 6021/003: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration files 6021/004: Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files 6021/005: Theodore W. Kheel Speeches and Articles 6021/007: Theodore W. Kheel Subject Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6021/009: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021/010: Theodore W. Kheel Additional Files 6021/011: Theodore W. Kheel Punta Cana Files 6021/012m: Invitation and Program for the Theodore W. Kheel Memorial Service 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 6194 OH: College of Labor and Employment Lawyers Interview with Theodore W. Kheel 6196 OH: New York City Central Labor Council Interview of Theodore W. Kheel for Central Archives 6207 OH: CLEL Video Oral History Project
Kheel, Theodore Woodrow
5767574
- AFL-CIO Labor Student Center Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center - Activities Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center - Minutes, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center 6039-A.5 Catalogs and Brochures (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mediation Employment Disputes Aliance for Education in Dispute Resolution, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mediating Employment Disputes Appendix (Alliance for Ed. In Dispute Resolution), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Foundation of Automation and Employment - Corporate Documents, 1962-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment Minutes, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- America Foundation on Automation and Employments Inc. Job Film Fair, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Automation House New Yorker, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CNB Press Release "Cable TV Special to Focus on Multinational Corporations", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The American Foundation on Automation and Employment - Contributions, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment - Geneva Speeches Booklet, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment - UFT Contribution, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment - Presidents Booklet, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Automation and Public Welfare Journal of the American Public Welfare Association April, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment - Maritime Dept., 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment - Board of Mediation, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Center for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Automation House - Magowan v. Automation House Litigation Binder, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Automation Home - Zuccotti Memo, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Automation House - Council on Foreign Relations, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- The Once Gallery, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- The Once Gallery - Automation House, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Automation House - Corporate Information, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Automation House - National Park Service Application, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Automation House - Autoworks, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Automation House - Jean Marc Levet, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Automation House - Bliebtreu, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Automation House - Bd of Directors, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment Inc. A Report to the President of the United States, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Automation House - Flyers, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Automation House News Clippings, art gallery items (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Automation House - Mortgage Loan Guarantee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Automation House Emily Landau, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- The Earth Times / The Earth Summit times, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Automation House Ad in NY Times (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The Earth Times / The Earth Summit Times, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Automation House - Acoustics and Noise Cont. Comp. / Weathermatic, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Automation House - Kneel Press Conf., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Beaubourg Foundation, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Corresp. #1, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Misc. 100-2, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Corresp. and Memos 6100-1, 1961-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return W 06100.000, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return 06100.000, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship fund Bylaws Cent. Of Incorp, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Blueberry Scholarship Fund Minutes, 1962-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Extra Copies and Notes, 1962-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Material 6100-6, 1962-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Minute Binder, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship fund Tax Return, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship fund Tax Return, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tac Return, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Annual Report, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship fund Tax Return, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Blueberry Cove Scholarship Fund Tax Return, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Center for Non-Broadcast Television - Change of Name from CNB to Foundation on Arts, Commutations, and Technology, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Center for Nonbroadcast TV - Videoconf. Seminar, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Center for Non-broadcast TV, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Channel L Working Group Inc., 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- World Vision International - CNB TV Telethon, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Center for Non-Broadcast Television at Automation House, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Broadway Drama Guild, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Channel L - CETA, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Seagram's Wine Tassting Show Oct 25, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- VOTRAK Public Affair Channel L (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Municipal Channel L, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tri-State Regional Planning Commission and Center for Non-Broadcast TV, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Broadcasting Revolution - Helene Zimmerman Show, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Artists Cable Project, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Artists Television Network, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Artists for NY, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Artists Cable Project, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Artists TV Network - Tom Freebairn, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Artists Cable Project - Rita Myers, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Artists Cable Project - Amy Greenfield, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Artists Cable Project - Various, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- American Dietetic Association CNB-TV, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Public Arts Network (NYC Council on the Arts), 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- St. John's University School of Law, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- St. John's - Grau vs. St. John's, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- St. John's University - CNB-TV Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- McGeorge School of Law CNB TV, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Columbia University, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- The Lost Million, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Pharmacists feasibility Study, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- arthritis Board of Governor's Meeting (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Over a Barrel, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Penn Schoen Associates, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Cable Networking in NYS, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Art Show, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Jack Hilton Incorporated, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Solaris, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Closing Statement, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Margaret De Cuevas, 1971-1985 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Margaret De Cuevas Lorrain - Correspondence File, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Margaret de Cuevas Lorrain - Pleadings Folder, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Margaret De Cuevas Larrain - Mortgage, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Margaret de Cuevas Larrain - Corresp. Copies, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Coastal Rhythms Corresp., 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Coastal Rhythms - Info Material, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Coastal Rhythms - Local Documents, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Coastal Rhythms - Reference Guide to the Marine Environment C., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Earth Pledge Foundation Vs. VIA, 1979-1997 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Earth Pledge Foundation vs. CIA, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Earth Pledge Foundation vs. CIA, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Earth Pledge Foundation v. CIA Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Earth Pledge Foundation v. CIA - Legal Research, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Frank Russell Co., 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Earth Pledge Foundation, 1995-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Financials, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - BCSC, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - BSCS DINNER (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Earth Times - Correspondence w/ Pranay Gupte, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Ashali Varma, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Earth Pledge - Maiorana, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Menezes, Vivek, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Abbasi, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Earth Summit - Closing Statement (Maurice Strong), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Division for Sustainable Media, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Renee Cox, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Earth Summit - Agreement w/ Ken Smalheiser (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Collective Purchasing Program, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Earth Times - Media List, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Human Settlements Conference, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Otherwise Book Review, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Sustainable Environment Associates, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Earthkind International, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Human Resources and the Internet (Earth Pledge Foundation), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Forum Future PRS Inc., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Earth Pledge - New England Aquarium - Aquasphere, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Re Vladimir Kartsev "Soyomultfilm", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Sustainable Development Mutual Fund, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Sustainable Dev. Syrup (Bierman - Lytle), 1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Sustainable Development Council, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Greenwire, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Promotion, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Earthfair, Inc., and Forum Future PRS, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- EPF - Agreement between Gallerie Litmann/Gallery Shop and Earth Summit Pledge, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Earth Pledge - "Workspace 2000", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Microsoft, 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Earth Pledge - Matthew Ultrino, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Environment Program, United Nations (UNEP Greening) - Close Manhattan, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Friends of the Earth v. Gov. Carey, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Center for Sustainable Cuisine, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Wisdom Keepers LLC, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Earth Pledge Foundation - Netscape, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- EPF - Chalmers, Irena - Sustainable Cuisine Book Folder 1, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- EPF - Chalmers, Irena - Sustainable Cuisine Book Folder 2, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- EPF Sustainable Cuisine Dinner, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc., 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc. - Proposal and Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - Corporate, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc. - Univ. of Arizona EAT Agriculture Project, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, Inc. Bylaws, Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc. - Chemical Bank, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - James O Rice Associates, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Experiments in Art _ Technology, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - Proposal for Pre-Investment Study, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Expert in Art and Technology - Grant Application, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - PepsiCo, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - IRS Penalty, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - EAT News, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Experiments in Art and Technology - Theodore W. Kheel, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- EAT - Duplicates and Drafts, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- EAT - Tax Exemption Letter (Box 5, Folder 20)
- EAT - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- EAT - Speech by Frank Stanton, President of CBS, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- EAT - L.J. Robinson Memos, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- EAT - Agreement w/ Amalgamated Lithographers of Amer. Local 1, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- EAT - Billy Kluwer Dinner, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- EAT - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- EAT - Documentary Collection of Project Proposals and Articles Jan - Oct, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Board of Mediation for Community Disputes Annual Report, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Foundation on Employee Health Medical Care and Welfare, Inc., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, Inc., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Foundation on Employee Health Medical Care and Welfare, Inc., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Scope and Contents
  Speeches, Clippings
- Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, Inc., 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)